### **Profile & Goals**

I moved from São Paulo to San Francisco for personal improvement, and I am currently pursuing my dreams of creating beautiful and easy to use software and hardware products by working and mastering the fields of Human-Computer Interactions: User Interface and Experience, Interactive Design and Usability.

# Gilmar Lira

#### www.purpleinteractive.co

August 1st, 1983

gilmar.lira@me.com +1-415-816-6641

1140 Sutter Street #514 San Francisco – CA. 94109 United States

# **Experience**

#### Apple Shop Specialist, Apple Brazil, São Paulo

2010-2011

- Opening of the biggest Apple shop in Latin America in 2010.
- Set up of a new, nation-wide, structure for merchandising and maintenance.
- Project management role in the installation of 55 new Apple shops
- Role in designing the user interface for the online supply management system

# Visual Merchandising Consultant, Apple Brazil, São Paulo 2008-2010

- Ensure the best brand experience for consumers at the store
- Execution, training and auditing on Apple's merchandising guidelines

# Personal Mac Consultant, Autonomous, São Paulo 2006–2008

• Worked with small and medium corporate clients and CEOs

# Apple Sales Promoter, Apple Brazil, São Paulo

2005

• Deep understanding of user interactions with Apple products

#### Web Designer / Programmer, Autonomous, São Paulo 2000–2004

- Visual design and coding of interactive web sites.
- User interfaces for database self-management (HTML/PHP/MySQL integration).

# **Education**

BA in Web Design and New Media (2015) - Academy of Art University, San Francisco.

Completed 4 semesters of BA in Graphic Design – Belas Artes University, São Paulo.

Completed 2 semesters of BS in Physics – University of São Paulo, São Paulo.

Visual Communication - Panamericana School of Art and Design, São Paulo 2002.

Basic of Art and Design - Panamericana School of Art and Design, São Paulo 2001.

### Skills

Advanced coding: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL and Wordpress.

Basic Cocoa Touch for iOS app development.

Very familiar with Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign and After Effects.

Really comfortable learning new technologies.

Fluent English, Spanish and Portuguese. Basic Mandarin (漢語).